<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on George Wood</title><link>https://gwo0d.github.io/tags/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on George Wood</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 21:01:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gwo0d.github.io/tags/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to improve your internet privacy (for free!)</title><link>https://gwo0d.github.io/blog/2021/08/how-to-improve-your-internet-privacy-for-free/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 21:01:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gwo0d.github.io/blog/2021/08/how-to-improve-your-internet-privacy-for-free/</guid><description>Note: I am not in any way affiliated with Cloudflare, I just think they&amp;rsquo;re cool!
Introduction As I&amp;rsquo;ve made clear in previous publications, I believe passionately that everyone should take their own digital hygiene and privacy seriously. In a world where users&amp;rsquo; personal data is the backbone of a $1.7 trillion industry [1], it is vitally important that the average person takes a stand.
Cloudflare is a company which (unless you&amp;rsquo;re a computer scientist) I&amp;rsquo;d forgive you for not recognising in the slightest; however, what they do is paramount to the smooth running of the internet.</description></item><item><title>Why I'm Moving to Mac</title><link>https://gwo0d.github.io/blog/2021/04/moving-to-mac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 16:19:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gwo0d.github.io/blog/2021/04/moving-to-mac/</guid><description>Foreword: After a long period of careful consideration, including an in-depth evaluation of my options, and considerable doubts, I&amp;rsquo;ve made the decision to move to macOS. For those of you who know me, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking, and rest assured my hypocrisy here does not escape me – I’ve been a diehard Windows user for as long as I’ve known what a computer is, and not only have I been loyal I have often been known to disparage those who prefer the Apple ecosystem; to those people I apologise wholeheartedly – as a carpenter once said “…forgive them, for they know not what they do.</description></item><item><title>An Overview of My Interests</title><link>https://gwo0d.github.io/blog/2020/11/my-interests/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gwo0d.github.io/blog/2020/11/my-interests/</guid><description>With a shiny new blog, and an exciting new hobby impending, I feel that a logical and prudent place to begin would be to discuss my interests within my chosen field – Computer Science.
Firstly, some foundational concepts; I am currently, have always been, and fully intend to continue being a colossal nerd. This fact is one which is immediately obvious to both those who already know me, and those who have only just met me alike.</description></item><item><title>Hello, world!</title><link>https://gwo0d.github.io/blog/2020/11/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:44:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gwo0d.github.io/blog/2020/11/hello-world/</guid><description>Greetings humans. This is my blog. Enjoy!
-George</description></item></channel></rss>