<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on George Wood</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on George Wood</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gwood.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GPG Tutorial - Command Line</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/10/gpg-tutorial-command-line/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 15:32:59 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/10/gpg-tutorial-command-line/</guid><description>Introduction My GPG key can be found here
In a world where there exists an ever-growing economy revolving around the sale and processing of individuals’ private data, tools like GNU Privacy Guard (GPG) offer a convenient way to take back control of what was once a well-respected right – individual privacy. I have spoken before on several occasions about why it is important to take your privacy seriously, and to be clear, GPG is not by any means an extensive solution; it is to a smaller extent a part of a much larger mosaic of tools needed to completely take control of your privacy.</description></item><item><title>C# Celsius/Fahrenheit Convertor</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/10/c-sharp-celsius-fahrenheit-convertor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 21:59:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/10/c-sharp-celsius-fahrenheit-convertor/</guid><description>Having recently started developing my C# programming skills, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d put together a simple Celsius/Fahrenheit convertor.
Code Available Here&amp;hellip;
License MIT License Copyright (c) 2021 George Wood Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;#34;Software&amp;#34;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions: The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.</description></item><item><title>How to improve your internet privacy (for free!)</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/08/how-to-improve-your-internet-privacy-for-free/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 21:01:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/08/how-to-improve-your-internet-privacy-for-free/</guid><description>Note: I am not in any way affiliated with Cloudflare, I just think they&amp;rsquo;re cool!
Introduction As I&amp;rsquo;ve made clear in previous publications, I believe passionately that everyone should take their own digital hygiene and privacy seriously. In a world where users&amp;rsquo; personal data is the backbone of a $1.7 trillion industry [1], it is vitally important that the average person takes a stand.
Cloudflare is a company which (unless you&amp;rsquo;re a computer scientist) I&amp;rsquo;d forgive you for not recognising in the slightest; however, what they do is paramount to the smooth running of the internet.</description></item><item><title>First Year - Life on the Inside</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/06/first-year-life-on-the-inside/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 19:12:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/06/first-year-life-on-the-inside/</guid><description>Introduction For myself and so many others, first year at university has been quite different to how we anticipated, in many ways for the worse. We spent much of our time indoors at home working remotely and watching endless pre-recorded lectures, and what little time we did have on-campus felt&amp;hellip; peculiar. Signs telling us all to &amp;ldquo;keep two metres apart!&amp;rdquo; and to &amp;ldquo;wipe down your desk before and after use!&amp;rdquo; dominated most unoccupied sections of wall, and what little space remained was consigned to sheepishly remind us about adjusted closing times - adjusted, of course, meaning considerably earlier than usual.</description></item><item><title>Why I'm Moving to Mac</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/04/moving-to-mac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 16:19:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/04/moving-to-mac/</guid><description>Foreword: After a long period of careful consideration, including an in-depth evaluation of my options, and considerable doubts, I&amp;rsquo;ve made the decision to move to macOS. For those of you who know me, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking, and rest assured my hypocrisy here does not escape me – I’ve been a diehard Windows user for as long as I’ve known what a computer is, and not only have I been loyal I have often been known to disparage those who prefer the Apple ecosystem; to those people I apologise wholeheartedly – as a carpenter once said “…forgive them, for they know not what they do.</description></item><item><title>BCrypt Login System - Proof of Concept</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/01/bcrypt-login-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:26:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2021/01/bcrypt-login-system/</guid><description>Following on from some of my previous content about data security, I&amp;rsquo;ve written a short proof of concept program showing how BCrypt can be used to securely store passwords.
I hope you like it, and feedback is always welcome.
main.py try: from user import User import os import time except ImportError: print(&amp;#34;\nError! Necessary libraries unavailable...\n&amp;#34;) def clear(): time.sleep(2.5) os.system(&amp;#39;cls&amp;#39; if os.name == &amp;#39;nt&amp;#39; else &amp;#39;clear&amp;#39;) username = input(&amp;#34;Username: &amp;#34;) password = input(&amp;#34;Password: &amp;#34;) # Example Username: testUser # Example Password: testPass user = User(username, password) go = True while go: try: menu = int(input(&amp;#34;\nEnter 1 to login\nEnter 2 to sign up\nEnter 3 to delete your credentials from the database\nEnter 4 to exit\n: &amp;#34;)) if menu == 1: result = user.</description></item><item><title>Data Security: A Comprehensive Guide</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2020/11/data-security-a-comprehensive-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 10:14:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2020/11/data-security-a-comprehensive-guide/</guid><description>Depreciated In a world where it is increasingly difficult to keep control of one&amp;rsquo;s own data, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a reasonably in-depth tutorial highlighting some of the core ideas behind data security.
This guide will focus on the GNU Privacy Guard (GPG), and will cover two main aspects: signing, and encryption.
Signing &amp;amp; Encryption: What are they? Signing Data signing is the the process of mathematically guaranteeing that a given file came from a given individual.</description></item><item><title>An Overview of My Interests</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2020/11/my-interests/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2020/11/my-interests/</guid><description>With a shiny new blog, and an exciting new hobby impending, I feel that a logical and prudent place to begin would be to discuss my interests within my chosen field – Computer Science.
Firstly, some foundational concepts; I am currently, have always been, and fully intend to continue being a colossal nerd. This fact is one which is immediately obvious to both those who already know me, and those who have only just met me alike.</description></item><item><title>Hello, world!</title><link>https://gwood.dev/blog/2020/11/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:44:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gwood.dev/blog/2020/11/hello-world/</guid><description>Greetings humans. This is my blog. Enjoy!
-George</description></item></channel></rss>